A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Sale of Ford Motor Company Stock FA725
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Sale of Ford Motor Company Stock
1959-1961
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA725
1.13 Cubic Feet 3 boxes (2 legal document containers and 1 half letter document container)
Scope and Contents
The files in this collection include financial reports, underwriting agreements, receipts, news articles, and correspondence related to the sale of Ford Motor Company stock by the Ford Foundation between 1959 and 1963. The files were maintained by the Ford Foundation's Treasurer's Office.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 2019 by the Ford Foundation and ingested by RAC as Accession 2019:072.
Arrangement
Arranged "as received" from the Ford Foundation.
Biographical / Historical
Starting in 1956, the Ford Foundation planned to diversify its portfolio through dispositions of its Ford Motor Company holdings. The Ford Motor Company stock was first offered to the public on January 18, 1956.
- Sale of Ford Motor Company Stock, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Public Offering, 1959 December (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
- Philco Acquisition, 1961 December 11 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Preliminary Prospectus - 2.25 Million Shares of Ford Motor Company, 1962 March 23 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Securities and Exchange Commission, Amendment No. 1 to Form S-1, Registration Statement under the Securities Act of 1993, Ford Motor Company, 1959 December 9 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 2 Million Shares of Ford Motor Company Common Stock, $5 Par Value, 1959 December 9 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Ford Motor Company Stock - Public Offering, 1961 June (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Securities and Exchange Commission, Form S-1, Registration Statement under the Securities Act of 1933, Ford Motor Company, 1961 June 27 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Analysis of Distribution - 2.75 Million Shares of Ford Motor Company Common Stock, $5 Par Value, 1961 June 27 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Sale of Ford Motor Company Stock - 2.75 Million Shares, 1961 June (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Ford Stock Sale - Morgan Guaranty Trust, 1961 July-August (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Ford Stock - Sold to Ford Motor Company - Re-Sold to Deutshe Bank, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- 2.75 Million Shares of Ford Motor Company Common Stock, $5 Par Value, 1961 June 27 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- 2.75 Million Shares of Ford Motor Company Common Stock, $5 Par Value - Agreement Among Underwriters, 1961 June 27 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Public Offering, 1962 April (Box 2, Folder 16-17, Box 3, Folder 18)
- Securities and Exchange Commission, Form S-1, Registration Statement under the Securities Act of 1933, Ford Motor Company, 1959 November 19; 1959 December 9 (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
- Affidavit of the Ford Foundation - Underwriting Agreement, 1961 July 6 (Box 3, Folder 21)